
Speaker 1  (00:07)
We define this is The New York Times Currently, defined electric It's given by key dot A Where a is the vector area, not the surface that you see on earth. And then These Scots that we simply take the dot product of E and A These points in that clip This union points this way to give you the maximum plus 0 points, and so we're in 2 minutes. If E is changing over which are here. 

Speaker 1  (00:58)
I'm looking direction or investment. Then, there's 2 integration. For us, most of the integration, we cannot be extremely free. 

Speaker 1  (01:09)
Just multiply E by some sort of energy So this is what we mean like that. The way to remember not worrying about the cross product is simply to realize that the area I'm a direction. That's 90° to surface. 

Speaker 1  (01:41)
We're looking at this area. This area has pointed out, it's This area points here. This area points here. 

Speaker 1  (01:52)
This area points down Why we certainly designed it now. The simple things like Canadian factor this makes our math equations to describe the physics a lot easier. So for example, in a case like this Number two areas to consider this one. 

Speaker 1  (02:23)
This one, the area through this larger local area will be the same as the flux through this area. That's the area that's in the direction of He used the side view. This seems to me, the doctor that's de. 

Speaker 1  (02:45)
The projection of the area along E that matter. If you here are some cases, this is a flat box. I showed you areas will point locally 90° to The physical feeling at the Q sea. 

Speaker 1  (03:07)
When you have current surfaces And indeed, again, normal of 19 points. 2 The surface is that point of interest that you're looking at. Then, we argued that if you take In field multiplied by the area. 

Speaker 1  (03:28)
For example, the E field of discharge, the distance of R will be kq over R², and it turns out that E falls off is one over R². A area goes up as one over R squar. So this key, one multiplied by this area would E2 multiplied by this area. 

Speaker 1  (03:53)
They always turn out to be simply equal to the charge, enclosed by those surfaces. This is the charge included by those people So charge includes divided by side, and it's It's generalized statement in order to Garcia's law It seems that the flux That goes through a Gaussian surface. Remember, Gaussian surface is an imagined surface. 

Speaker 1  (04:30)
It's not a real thing that you can book. It's going to be a lot of things so I can imagine this field in Italy. So the flux coming out in Gaussian, surface is simply equal to the charge closed divided by this. 

Speaker 1  (04:52)
And I told you that this is almost like you're And 1 oz, it's like seeing, if I put a net around this room or if I counted one of you going out of this room. On what's inside the room? What is this? 

Speaker 1  (05:13)
But if I put a room around the table, these 2 rows Then, as people go out Don't flux of people. It would simply be different. But for that same If you don't enlose a charge, the flux is 0 and it close in charge. 

Speaker 1  (05:33)
The flux is simply the charge enclosed divided by signal naught to emphasize that, for example, consider this This video resolution problem 32 from chapter 22. This area is a charge exactly at the center of this cube. And it's 3 micro groups, minus And they are asking, how much flux? 

Speaker 1  (06:05)
It's fastening through one of the faces. Doesn't matter which case sequencer. Now you're talking, watch flowers, flux integration, but there's nothing You also see About when you have students, DNA that the clubs Essentially, Q and close. 

Speaker 1  (06:27)
For example Since it's exactly at the center, the flux through each base will be the same. So Galaxy's simply To what they think is this These 16. It's a total flat. 

Speaker 1  (06:48)
The total flux is charged and close I'd be reminded by observing. 

Speaker 1  (07:07)
Let's say it's Most people have mentioned as long as we understand what this is See, so today, we do some problems. Illustrating how it's done in different geometries okay? We are going to do this integration. 

Speaker 1  (07:31)
E.ba. Which is the flock? There were such electric. 

Speaker 1  (07:41)
What you forget about the substitute electric. We're going to do so many times that let's just go through once and then we want to repeat saying the same things again. So let's consider a little area. 

Speaker 1  (07:59)
Except it is right This area is going to point regularly out And this is DA This evening is dead. The effort at that point. It's also going to be point in Greenwich. 

Speaker 1  (08:38)
Therefore, e.da e.dk. Seems to be our We're seeing direction row at Eva. Cosine, beta is just Eda. 

Speaker 1  (09:00)
But if you're going around a sphere, it's very good to develop the surface. These should be the same at this point. If we discount from the charge, the charge is at the center. 

Speaker 1  (09:16)
Therefore, I can take E out of this integral sum because it's the constant Da integrated more is spherical surface. I see an unfold while I'm Power supplier students. That's it. 

Speaker 1  (09:44)
So next time I write integration over a spherical gaubsian surface I am the job right from here to here. Okay, and that is the explanation which doctors have done. Okay, now we are set to do Any questions is what problems you keep repeating? 

Speaker 1  (10:17)
So let's consider a thin spherical shell. There's nothing here that is empty. I think what I've been thinking about. 

Speaker 1  (10:31)
Thin skin skin, not inside. And then we put some charge there. The only place we can put charge is on the physical body of this shell. 

Speaker 1  (10:46)
So nothing is nothing here, so the whole charge is on the surface. And it doesn't matter if it insulating or a conductor this physically gave something to put here, whether it's a conductor or insultivity shell, the charge has to go or it's Surface. Or if it's a solid Sphere may not matter, so it's a conducting sphere. 

Speaker 1  (11:24)
In this case. If you're trying to put any charges in something, suppose you won't put a charge here. It's not a mistake inside the body. 

Speaker 1  (11:38)
The reason is that like charges repail. And inside a nothing symbol charges are free to move In the extraordinary movie so if you try to put any charges inside, it would go in and release in some charge, it's not going to stay there yet. Like George's rebel, there'll be moving away from each other until they end up at the surface. 

Speaker 1  (12:18)
So, these charges are not on state here. Everything answers the surface. So let's meet this review this R. 

Speaker 1  (12:36)
And then suppose we are Western power. So we are inside, so let's imagine a Gaussian surface Here all here is Inside is empty of charge. So we figure out E The dark A. 

Speaker 1  (13:04)
I need to go to 2000 What's the cute and closed by this green surface? I'm sure this is Cheryl, technically, if you could go inside and grab back much volume, what are you going to get away with? So there's This is 0 because you've been closed to 0. 

Speaker 1  (13:44)
Okay, thank you for the warmth of water. For our lesson R is 0 There's no effort inside the shell or the solid conducting sphere. How about outside? 

Speaker 1  (14:00)
So now I go outside So if humans are I've seen the surface now. So this meat R is RR is greater than NFL Before you bite the same thing in the game. A equal to 4 Pi R² E is Q and closed If you impose divided by You let down the home. 

Speaker 1  (14:52)
So humans is the whole charge. If you surround it a child Q then that's what does this go? So E For our greatest level. 

Speaker 1  (15:09)
Can you please give me true? 4 Pi R² sine naught, which is K through R² But this is precisely the E few the point charge that the distance of it So look at this in all these cases, the E free inside is 0. But as soon as you get outside It's soon as you are here. 

Speaker 1  (15:44)
Outside of the charger. I've discovered the chart. So here is here. 

Speaker 1  (15:54)
So here, some charges will enclose some charges really far away. And you see, a flight prudence looks crazy. Because God does not tell you that as soon as you get out of that spherical charge distribution. 

Speaker 1  (16:10)
It, and as if the whole charge was sitting right there. This distribution is a matter The effect of whether it's a shell or a solid connecting sphere, once you're outside, it behaves as if this was all sitting at the And that's what this expression tells you So now let's take In case it is case that's different from others. In this case, we have a insulating sphere. 

Speaker 1  (16:56)
That means charges stay put in Putin. Even if they want to rebel each other charges do not move inside an insulator. So, the neighbors doing Are Western? 

Speaker 1  (17:17)
So this is And I am going to put The garbage can social sphere. And I'll be interested in the charge that discussing surface warming It comes. So being encountered out this much I went to charge when you get away with So to do that, we first defined A In all human So today, then we talked about last time, in this case it's going to be 2 We wind up by the 4 / 3RQ. 

Speaker 1  (18:10)
During the charges of its own This is here. So good luck. When we write Garcia's law in your Darwin. 

Speaker 1  (18:30)
It's good to be equal quality R². It's equal to 2 and close You want to write China? Few includes will be the bargaining of this red hedged scale. 

Speaker 1  (18:51)
Bye bye bye RE royal, okay? Remember. Rome. 

Speaker 1  (19:03)
As the global charge divided by the one, so charge is given by rho times the one room So this is the role, and this is the volume we are interested. Divided by excellent knot. If you look at the way we define it. 

Speaker 1  (19:35)
Can you give Divide divided by 4 / 1 Tr T and the other side of the UK So fold by by 3 goes away. I ended up willing. 2 4 3 2 2 0 2. 

Speaker 1  (20:13)
Well, look, there is an R square on this side. So this R² row gets rid of one, sorry, 2 hours R², so let me write this here, and then I want Square is 2 papers across the hands 

Speaker 1  (20:50)
Here you go. All over here. 

Speaker 1  (21:11)
You remind us immediately like that. And then what you could also write this aside as well? I'm wondering what's It's the same thing. 

Speaker 1  (21:36)
I'm writing Dubai and 4 / 2 multiplies. By 3 have changed nothing. But now, if you look at Q uid by this, that's rho, so you can leave it as this expression, or if somebody doesn't tell you what U is. 

Speaker 1  (21:54)
But tells you what growth is So this is what happens inside a installing sphere. For all greater than RPLM Now on your outside So if you were to Draw for imagining surface outside And I gained right E dot engaged here. Are ranges than ours? 

Speaker 1  (22:39)
You're outside of the Charged sphere. Then, you're enclosing the whole thing. 3 4 8 4 2. 

Speaker 1  (23:08)
And D is a known QOUO Squ square squared, or PUR squared, which again Is the key field of the point charge away from it? So this is what we learn. Doesn't beggar? 

Speaker 1  (23:32)
How the charge is distributed? It could be a shell Whether made out of insulator or econoductor it could be a conducting sphere. It could be an insulating sphere as long as you're outside. 

Speaker 1  (23:56)
They all behave not like the spheres of the shells. They all behave as if there was a point of charge at the center. Inside, they behave differently inside Inside a shell, what I will coin conduct a war insulator if you deserve and then if you is also 0 in the conducting shell. 

Speaker 1  (24:33)
Open up in solid sphere. Actually, if you do the 0 inside economic, no matter what it's saying So we can Look all of this together in one simple diet. If I were to plot E There's a function of R This being the center of spreading charge industry for The field is 0 or 0 Shells? 

Speaker 1  (25:15)
Conducting foreign war. We're doughing. Plus I saw this. 

Speaker 1  (25:31)
Outside we each are Here these are. If you go away from R We follow our split, just like it's Proportions, over our square square. If it's so, this is true for everything. 

Speaker 1  (26:00)
Won' It's very cool. So it's distinctly using The inside an insulating sphere Inside the insulator sphere Yeah, I mean. It advises limit leader R. 

Speaker 1  (26:22)
Rho is a constant field, of course, is a constant opposite constant. So if you double RE becomes double So V goes like this Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. 

Speaker 1  (27:00)
This is all the summary of whatever I just said. So for R once you're outside Old fatal charge and distributions act like a point charge. Sitting at the original So what we are doing in problem, of course, we give you these equations, so you can put the number But the fact that the efing inside a conductor is 0 is not an equation. 

Speaker 1  (27:37)
So make a mark somewhere that helps me do A boy boy making mistakes if he inside a conductor this year. Ok, the next one, suppose we have they will call an infinite sheet. These things are not mathematical complexities. 

Speaker 1  (28:01)
We call something infinity, because that gangs see that and and I can't see this end. Then, let me see infinite sheet. So That means. 

Speaker 1  (28:18)
I can see this. I can see that This angle is less than 180 by showing this one is not incorrigin. What do you want to keep meeting here? 

Speaker 1  (28:32)
And now I cannot see that hand and I cannot see that I said within like a few millimeters of it. The Buffett obviously either can. Thank you. 

Speaker 1  (28:48)
Thank you. So many kids finishing, so we'll be making it in that sense. This is infinite. 

Speaker 1  (28:56)
As long as you don't go over there, right? Compared with dimensions, you stay in close enough terms. So that's what we mean by infinite. 

Speaker 1  (29:08)
This is not A Actual infinitesimal. Okay, so here is A The sheath of charge very, very large And here is the side view that edge view of the same thing. Let's see what here is the sheet. 

Speaker 1  (29:31)
I'm looking at it like it's But if you look at this is going to go like this. What were you from the project challenge? I'll just draw a few rock. 

Speaker 1  (29:50)
Crowds So that's the EV So what I'm going to do The sheet of charge I'm gonna have to put by gabs here in someplace for us. I like this. I'm going to go right through this charge cheek. 

Speaker 1  (30:15)
Remember, the Gaussian surface is dimensional. So my Bobby's in the surface looks like this. Cuts it like this here if I were to drawing it big like that. 

Speaker 1  (30:38)
We've got this embargo in surface. 

Speaker 1  (30:52)
So imagine It doesn't have to be surrender, though, by the way, in this case. If I do that So here is the psi view The edge U and here is what I remember. Let's see what you see. 

Speaker 1  (31:27)
Thank you so much. We do the right to be good to If you look at the edges or the faces of the surveinder. Fear. 

Speaker 1  (31:45)
I can just see on the shoot like this. If you look at the current surfaces here Here the energy of points in this graph. This is the big area of the faces. 

Speaker 1  (32:11)
So again, sheet is right there. This goes right through it. These areas are in the direction This evening is in that direction. 

Speaker 1  (32:23)
The E is going this way. All the areas on the surface, whether here or here or here are 90° towards feeding here. So when you do the integration EBay, A All of the guardians of Christ, which happens to be a surlender. 

Speaker 1  (32:55)
You get no contribution from the curved surfaces. There's no best include the curved surfaces. It's cutting through the flat faces. 

Speaker 1  (33:09)
And let's say each phase was a so this is a so I'm going to get Ea. It would be space Because E as We are appointing the same direction and E gay from here. We are also pointing in the same direction. 

Speaker 1  (33:35)
I get nothing from the curved surfaces is the 80 years of 90°, 2 edges. This should be 2 enclosed. Would you like to or not? 

Speaker 1  (33:52)
Human clothes is going to be The surface So those density Multiply by area that is, the charge include the charge includes. Would be whatever is contained? In fact where the Gaussian surface intersected I'd like tonight Saturday night. 

Speaker 1  (34:29)
So, it didn't really matter. How big you got in surface? Water is medium pensions out. 

Speaker 1  (34:36)
So the EV feed near a charge sheet That's what you want to do. It's depending on the charge. Describe the machine and again. 

Speaker 1  (34:52)
We are assuming because there's no distance dependency It is a matter if you are here or here or earlier here. As long as Compared to the size of a sheet 

Speaker 1  (35:22)
So again, I want to emphasize that all these integrations are really treated here or in the case of the sphere. So here's one particular technological we have. If long line charge as, for example, a Caso line, essentially long line of charge. 

Speaker 1  (35:52)
Slowly still a long line of charge. Here's the side view, and let's imagine that lambda. Is the linear? 

Speaker 1  (36:07)
So hard dancing. Here this is the edge you are saying. If we will go like this 

Speaker 1  (36:31)
It's negative charge to flip. The directions. So in this case, I will draw in Gaussian surface And if the surrounds The wire. 

Speaker 1  (36:48)
Hey it's sulimin's name. Here we can apply this Let this L. And the radius is far So I've drawn because it's so fixing imagined a cylinder drawn around This line charge. 

Speaker 1  (37:20)
If you look at The E feat distribution. As you can imagine, any area on the surface of a cylinder Do you think it is good? We'll look for a cylinder. 

Speaker 1  (37:43)
The flag faces the new area. According to this way, or that way The curb surfaces. You draw a normal at every point. 

Speaker 1  (37:52)
Locally media points 90° to occur surface. So in this case There's no flux passing through the flag faces. This keyspond point can read these millennial. 

Speaker 1  (38:13)
So when you write E dot da The only contribution you get It's from the curve surface to this is E times 2IR. William's hell. It is a radius of R. 

Speaker 1  (38:40)
I am good. In length, L so this is 2 by R so if I cut it over We have a rectangle of psi, 2 PHI, R and then F That's what vanished. So that's the area. 

Speaker 1  (38:56)
This has to be equal to Q. The close Rise pipes out of the world, Q and clothes will be lambda times health. Lender is the linear charge density. 

Speaker 1  (39:08)
That's the charge total charge divided by the total length So L we contain a charge, which is lambda L Again, now doesn't affect your results. It's some choice, therefore EVE It's the key field of a line job. We use it maybe about 3 chapters from now where we talk about cylindrical capacitors. 

Speaker 1  (40:08)
Let me just quickly show you this. In your yeah, I'm not asking me to go back up to this termin. Yeah, thank you. 

Speaker 1  (40:44)
So you will do this in your presentations so that we introduce you to the truth. So what was instead of a wire? So you had fat cylinder like this It's really this is offensive. 

Speaker 1  (41:13)
And the small were just showed you a small section of it. Since it's a fat slender, we will define a vulgan. Shores. 

Speaker 1  (41:29)
Density. Which is So somebody has given us the role I would like to find out the feed inside this The outsider, and this is made out of insulator. Let me charge his statement there you need to be. 

Speaker 1  (41:59)
And the charges are uniform moves towards you. I suppose I go in So I'm going to draw the calcium surface. Inside the death It's limb. 

Speaker 1  (42:19)
L. So this ring here is a small R Dude, I'm not going to Dwight here because you can get crowded. But remember, the key field is going to go bigly out, just like I think this was a broad story symmetrical wire. 

Speaker 1  (42:44)
This thing so I'm not showing you the N UN U would look like this, and the E view would go regularly. So when I write e.ba The recovery in the surface When you eat Em E Group eyes are M just like a radioactive, typically like this. The edges don't contribute and the curved surface continue. 

Speaker 1  (43:27)
2 Pi R. L. This is cumulative. 

Speaker 1  (43:39)
The molecule enclosed will be equal to the volume of this cylinder. The volume of this cylinder will be Pi. R. 

Speaker 1  (43:47)
Squared L Pi R² is the area of the phase. I'm multiplied by length because the volume and rho is the density. Divided by Again? 

Speaker 1  (44:08)
L is a beautiful consequence of choosing anything we like Trying to win and not E It's going to be Roll, go wrong. I'm The wide and broad and I'm upside when you're not let me see why it's In one of the Rs disappears, you have an R² here you have R here, so this is just an R is rho. Int. 

Speaker 1  (44:53)
So this is called R less than power. You're using it, doing it for my presentational vessel once you go outside. Let me redraw that here. 

Speaker 1  (45:07)
I'll draw the one thing. Fat and wire, I'm out here. So it's the same wire without just deploying because I want to go outside. 

Speaker 1  (45:23)
If you draw them So for his outside, this involves in the surface of lingu. This part doesn't change at all. This is just the same, so now you can get it. 

Speaker 2  (45:43)
Thank you so much. 

Speaker 1  (45:47)
Hell, this is all about it. I think it's just the integration of college in surface. But now 2 enclosed. 

Speaker 1  (46:03)
It's become Just because you're all unique. Gods in surface is big. The charge is not true. 

Speaker 1  (46:15)
Our Belgian volume, it's just the charge. That's contained in this section. Thank you. 

Speaker 1  (46:22)
Wireless, and then that's volume will be 2 5 8 1 2. We define R square L. You see earlier at the close Find small R square. 

Speaker 1  (46:40)
Because this was your girlfriend's intervention. But here we're not going to put R because in surface because the charge is contained only in this solid A piece of wire, so this is row Pi R² L that's the blogging of this wire. That's the charge of density divided by 2000 I'm being gained. 

Speaker 1  (47:11)
Now, the way 5 notes away now this is growing Our screen is clearly I mean, so we're talk This tells you that the farther you go from the races of this. If you will stop dropping predators. Here's here. 

Speaker 1  (47:38)
I don't think it's the efi field was increasingly power. So for the fat wire, if you does this It increases the ability And then he drops off. Not as fast as it did for a spherical charge to distribution Derek fellows, one of R² and guaranteed. 

Speaker 1  (48:07)
This is what it does for the accelerated. 

Speaker 1  (49:44)
That's 
